<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<typeSystemDescription xmlns="http://uima.apache.org/resourceSpecifier">
    <name>hw1-lmahler-typesystem</name>
    <description>This is the UIMA CAS Type System Descriptor for a sample information processing pipeline. The pipeline contains 5 stages:

1. Test Element Annotation: The system will read in the input file as a UIMA CAS and annotate the question and answer spans. Each answer annotation will also record whether or not the answer is correct.
Input Types: N/a (text file as input)
Output Types: Sentence, Question, Answer

2. Token Annotation: The system will annotate each token span in each question and answer (break on whitespace and punctuation).
Input Types: Sentence
Output Types: Token

3. NGram Annotation: The system will annotate 1-, 2- and 3-grams of consecutive tokens.
Input Types: Token
Output Types: NGram

4. Answer Scoring: The system will incorporate a component that will assign an answer score annotation to each answer. The answer score annotation will record the score assigned to the answer.
Input Types: Question, Answer
Output Types: AnswerScore

5. Evaluation: The system will sort the answers according to their scores, and calculate precision at N (where N is the total number of correct answers).
Input Types: AnswerScore
Output Types: N/a (text file or print results to screen)</description>
    <version>1.0</version>
    <vendor/>
  <types>
    <typeDescription>
      <name>qa.AbstractAnnotation</name>
      <description>The most abstract Annotation type in this namespace. All other Annotations inherit from AbstractAnnotation.</description>
      <supertypeName>uima.tcas.Annotation</supertypeName>
      <features>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>source</name>
          <description>The UIMA Analysis Engine (or other source) that generated this annotation.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.String</rangeTypeName>
        </featureDescription>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>confidence</name>
          <description>The confidence level of the Annotation. Although there is no upper or lower bound on this feature, the confidence level is expected to fall within the range [0.0, 1.0].</description>
          <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.Double</rangeTypeName>
        </featureDescription>
      </features>
    </typeDescription>
    <typeDescription>
      <name>qa.AbstractSpanAnnotation</name>
      <description>An abstract Annotation type for Annotations that cover text spans (as opposed to other media such as images or video).</description>
      <supertypeName>qa.AbstractAnnotation</supertypeName>
      <features>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>begin</name>
          <description>The offset (from the beginning of the document) that indicates where the text span begins.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.Integer</rangeTypeName>
        </featureDescription>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>end</name>
          <description>The offset (from the beginning of the document) that indicates where the text span ends.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.Integer</rangeTypeName>
        </featureDescription>
      </features>
    </typeDescription>
    <typeDescription>
      <name>qa.Sentence</name>
      <description>An Annotation type used to annotate sentences.</description>
      <supertypeName>qa.AbstractSpanAnnotation</supertypeName>
    </typeDescription>
    <typeDescription>
      <name>qa.Token</name>
      <description>An Annotation type used to annotate tokens within sentences.</description>
      <supertypeName>qa.AbstractSpanAnnotation</supertypeName>
    </typeDescription>
    <typeDescription>
      <name>qa.Question</name>
      <description>An Annotation type used to annotate questions.</description>
      <supertypeName>qa.Sentence</supertypeName>
    </typeDescription>
    <typeDescription>
      <name>qa.Answer</name>
      <description>An Annotation type used to annotate answers to questions.</description>
      <supertypeName>qa.Sentence</supertypeName>
      <features>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>isCorrect</name>
          <description>Indicates that this Answer is the correct Answer to a Question.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.Boolean</rangeTypeName>
        </featureDescription>
      </features>
    </typeDescription>
    <typeDescription>
      <name>qa.NGram</name>
      <description>An Annotation type used to annotate NGrams (series of consecutive Tokens). Although this type inherits from AbstractSpanAnnotation (thus annotating a single span of text), the elements feature stores an array of all Tokens covered by the text span.</description>
      <supertypeName>qa.AbstractSpanAnnotation</supertypeName>
      <features>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>elements</name>
          <description>Stores an array of all Tokens covered by the text span.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.FSArray</rangeTypeName>
          <elementType>qa.Token</elementType>
          <multipleReferencesAllowed>true</multipleReferencesAllowed>
        </featureDescription>
      </features>
    </typeDescription>
    <typeDescription>
      <name>qa.AnswerScore</name>
      <description>An Annotation type used to annotate Answers with their scores (computed during the answer scoring phase).</description>
      <supertypeName>qa.Sentence</supertypeName>
      <features>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>score</name>
          <description>The score of the Answer, computed during the answer scoring phase.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.Double</rangeTypeName>
        </featureDescription>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>answer</name>
          <description>A pointer to the Answer associated with this AnswerScore.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>qa.Answer</rangeTypeName>
        </featureDescription>
      </features>
    </typeDescription>
  </types>
</typeSystemDescription>
